lexis.com 2012-12-12

# Privacy Policy - LexisNexis

_(Last updated 8/30/2011)_

To underscore our commitment to privacy and our vision that good privacy is good business, we have adopted this Online Privacy Policy for the websites that link to this privacy policy, including but not limited to Lexis.com, LexisNexis CourtLink, LexisNexis Law Schools, LexisNexis Store, and LexisNexis TotalPatent, ("our websites"). You may also have been directed to this Online Privacy Policy from other websites owned or operated by LexisNexis, a division of Reed Elsevier, Inc., and/or its affiliates ("LexisNexis") that have adopted this Online Privacy Policy. Other LexisNexis websites may operate under their own privacy notices such as www.lexisnexis.com/risk and affiliated hypersites identified in the lexisnexis.com/risk online privacy policy. 

This Online Privacy Policy only applies to information collected through our websites. It does not apply to information collected in any other way, including information collected offline. Other LexisNexis websites may operate under their own online privacy policies. Our websites are not directed at children under the age of 13.

### INFORMATION COLLECTION

**I. Personally Identifiable Information**

Personally identifiable information ("PII") collected with your consent may include, for example, name, mailing address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, occupation, any information you provide to us when placing an order or using the services on our websites, any responses you choose to provide to survey questions, information provided in connection with subscribing to a newsletter, any inquiries you may make through our websites, or any other PII you provide to us through our websites. 

In addition, we collect information, including PII, in connection with attempts to log-in to our products and services through our websites and the actions taken by users while they are logged into our online products and services. This may include, for example, collecting information pertaining to searches conducted, the pages visited during the online session, and any or all other interactions that the user may have with our systems while the user is logged into one of our products or services. 

**II. Cookies**

Our websites may use browser "cookies", local shared objects (also known as "Flash cookies") or other technologies.

Browser cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer. Browser cookies, for example, may be used by our websites to help us manage your visit to our websites or determine whether a visitor is unique or whether a visitor has viewed our websites before. While most browsers are set to accept cookies by default, you can set yours to refuse cookies or to alert you before accepting them. Your browser manufacturer has information on changing the default setting for your specific browser. Deleting or refusing to accept cookies from our websites, however, may limit your ability to use some portions of our websites which require the use of cookies to operate effectively.

Our websites also may use local shared objects, also known as "Flash cookies" to store your preferences or display content based upon what you view on our websites to personalize your visit. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here: [http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/  
settings_manager.html#117118.](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118)

Third Parties, with whom we may partner to provide certain features on our websites or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, may use browser cookies or Flash cookies to collect and store information.

**III. Non-personally Identifiable Information**

Our websites also may collect non-personally identifiable information. For example, as you browse our websites we may collect information about your visit. Via Web server logs, for example, we may monitor statistics such as: the number of people that visit our websites, which page(s) are visited on our websites, from which domain our visitors come (e.g., google.com, microsoft.com), and which browsers people use to visit our websites (e.g. Safari, Microsoft Internet Explorer, etc.). We also may compile statistics that show the numbers and frequency of visitors to our websites and its individual pages. These aggregated statistics may be used internally to improve our websites and for product development and marketing purposes generally. The aggregated statistics may also be provided to advertisers and other third parties, but again, the statistics contain no PII.

Our websites also may use outsourcing programs to assist us in analyzing this data to better our websites.

### INFORMATION USE AND CONSUMER CHOICE

The information collected by our websites may be used for responding to your inquiries and otherwise corresponding with you, for processing transactions you request, maintaining your account (if you have one), for other purposes permitted by your organization's agreement(s) (if any) for products and services, to maintain the security and integrity of our websites, products and services, for the purpose of conducting market research or surveys on behalf of LexisNexis, and for the administration, review and/or the improvement of the content of our websites, products or services.

We may use information about searches or submissions that users provide to us as part of our customer care functions to contact you in response to your comments or inquiries, as part of the maintenance of your account with us (if you have one), or in order to complete a transaction that you requested. In addition, we may also use this type of information to enhance our products and services or to communicate to you about products and services that may be of interest to you, but we will offer you an opportunity not to receive such communications. Similarly, if you sign up to receive newsletters or to be added to one of our mailing lists, you will be able to "unsubscribe" from these communications at any time.

We may enhance or merge your information collected on our websites with data from third parties for purposes of marketing products or services to you. 

We may offer you a "refer-a-friend" option to refer our websites or information about our products and services to others. If you choose to use our referral service, we will ask you for your friend's name and e-mail address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time e-mail message with information about the product or service and/or inviting him or her to visit our websites. This message may include your name and/or e-mail address and any optional message that you elect to send along with our e-mail. We will not retain the information that you provide as part of this referral service (although we may retain your friend's e-mail address if he or she requests to receive additional information or e-mail messages from us).

### ONWARD TRANSFER

We may disclose information you provide to us to third parties in order to complete a transaction that you requested or as otherwise permitted by your organization's customer agreement(s) (if any).

We may also outsource some tasks, including the operation of certain website functions that require access to information you supply online and information about your visits to our websites. In such cases, however, we require that the companies acting on our behalf institute safeguards to protect the confidentiality of your information. 

If our company or our assets are acquired by another company, that company will assume responsibility for the personal information collected by us through our websites and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding the information collected through our websites, as described in this privacy policy.

If you choose to make information available to other people through instant messages, group chats, electronic mail messages, blog postings, your networking profile (if any), registering for an event, or by joining groups or using other networking functions that we may offer on our websites, this information will be visible to third parties. Please take care in deciding what information you choose to make available through these mechanisms, as we do not control the manner in which recipients or persons who may see the information may use or re-disclose the information that you choose to provide.

Finally, please note that we may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary in order to comply with the law or legal process or is pertinent to judicial or governmental investigations or proceedings.

### ACCESS AND CORRECTION

We strive to maintain the accuracy of the PII collected through our websites. We will provide you (whether you are a consumer or a customer) with access to PII you provide through our websites for as long as we maintain that information in a readily accessible format. We will also work with you to correct any PII you submitted to us.

If you wish to access PII that you have submitted through our websites or to request the correction of any inaccurate PII you have submitted through our websites, please use the mechanisms provided by our websites or send an e-mail to: [Privacy.Information.Mgr@lexisnexis.com.](mailto:Privacy.Information.Mgr@lexisnexis.com)

The access and correction provisions of this Online Privacy Policy only apply to PII collected from you through our websites. 

Individuals that are interested in information about how to access and/or request the correction of personal information LexisNexis maintains about them (such as public record information, insurance claims information, or information for employment background screening) for potential inclusion in information products and services can visit [www.lexisnexis.com/privacy](http://www.lexisnexis.com/privacy) or [personalreports.lexisnexis.com](http://personalreports.lexisnexis.com/).

### SECURITY

We have put in place administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the information that we collect from you through our websites. In the event we request or transmit sensitive information, such as credit card information or Social Security Numbers, our processes are designed to use industry standard, secure socket layer ("SSL") encryption. We also limit access to PII to those employees who need access in order to carry out their job responsibilities. 

### OTHER WEBSITES

This Online Privacy Policy only applies to our websites as defined in the opening paragraph and other LexisNexis websites that have adopted this Online Privacy Policy. Our websites, however, may include links to other websites which may be operated by other LexisNexis companies or by third parties and are subject to other privacy policies. If you visit another website, we recommend that you review the online privacy policy of that website to determine how the operator of that website will handle personal information collected through that website.

For your convenience, for example, we may offer links to online tools which allow you to share content from our websites with third parties or sites of your choosing, such as Share This, Facebook, or Twitter. Your use of such tools, sometimes called "widgets," is subject to the privacy policy applicable to the tool or widget that you use. 

### POLICY CHANGES

We may revise this Online Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any material changes to this Online Privacy Policy, the date of the most recent revision will be indicated above so that you can determine whether there have been any material revisions since your last visit. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Online Privacy Policy, please contact us at:  
LexisNexis  
Privacy, Security and Compliance Organization  
PO Box 933  
Dayton, Ohio 45401  
Telephone: 1-800-831-2578  
Email: Privacy.Information.Mgr@lexisnexis.com
